A Guide to the Edward Lawrie Tatum papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA133
Rockefeller Archive Center
Edward Lawrie Tatum papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1936-1975
Rockefeller Archive Center
Tatum, Edward Lawrie
Rockefeller University
FA133
25 Cubic Feet
63 boxes, 3 bound volumes, 3 Packages and 2 Film reels
Biographical/Historical note
Edward Lawrie Tatum, 1909-1975, a biochemical geneticist, Member and Professor at the Rockefeller University from 1957 until his death in 1975. His field of research was the study of the genetics and metabolism of bacteria, yeast and molds. His research was aimed at a clear understanding of how genes determine, at the molecular level, the characteristics of living organisms. His special interests were the nutrition and metabolism of insects and microorganisms and the biochemistry and genetics of microorganisms. Some of his most significant research results were: identification of thiamine as a growth factor for propionic acid bacteria (with H.G. Wood); isolation and identification of kynurenine as an eye-color hormone in Drosophila (with G.W. Beadle); discovery of biochemical mutations in Neurospora (with G.W. Beadle); biochemical mutations in bacteria; gene recombination in Escherichia coli (with J.S. Lederberg); biosynthesis of tryptophan (with D.M. Bonner).
In 1958 he shared the Nobel prize in medicine and physiology with G.W. Beadle and J. Lederberg for their contributions in biochemical genetics.
Biographical Note
1909 Born December 14 Boulder, Colorado
1925-1927 Attended the University of Chicago
1931 A.B. (Chemistry) University of Wisconsin
1932 M.S. (Microbiology) University of Wisconsin
1934 Ph. D (Biochemistry) University of Wisconsin (under E.B. Fred and W.H. Peterson)
1934-1936 Research assistant in chemistry and bacteriology, University of Wisconsin
1936-1937 General Education Board Fellow in bacteriological chemistry, University of Utrecht, Holland
1937-1941 Research associate in biology, Stanford University
1941-1945 Assistant professor of biology, Stanford University
1945-1946 Associate professor of botany, Yale University
1946-1948 Professor of microbiology, Yale University
1948-1956 Professor of biology, Stanford University
1956-1957 Professor and Head, Department of biochemistry, Stanford University
1957-1975 Member and Professor at RU (formerly RI)
1975 Died November 5 New York City
Awards, lectureships and honors
1946 Herter lectureship, New York University
1953 Remsen award of the American Chemical Society
1958 Nobel prize in medicine and physiology shared with G.W. Beadle and J. Lederberg
Honorary degrees
1963 Gustav Adolphus College
1964 Rutgers University
1964 University of Wisconsin
1965 University of Notre Dame
1965 Trinity College
1968 Yeshiva University
1971 Northwestern University
Member of: American Association for the Advancement of Science, American Chemical Society, American Philosophical Society, American Society of Biological Chemists, Botanical Society of America, Genetics Society, National Academy of Sciences (Elected to in 1952), New York Academy of Sciences, Harvey Society (President 1964-1965), Sigma Xi
RU Committees Faculty committee on lectures, Faculty committee to review policies and practices regarding faculty appointments and promotions, Biological sciences committee (Chairman 1968-1969), Honorary degree committee, Faculty committees involving students
Scientific committees, etc. American Cancer Society, Research advisory board, City of Hope Medical Center, Scientific advisory panel, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory of Quantitative Biology, Bd. of Trustees (Chairman), Jackson Memorial Laboratory, Board of scientific consultants, Merck and Co., Consultant in microbiology, National Institutes of Health, Genetics study section (Chairman), National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis (becomes National Foundation): Committee on virus research and epidemiology; Committee on research fellowships, National Research Council: Committee on growth, Genetics panel (Chairman); Merck fellowship board; Biology council, National Science Foundation: National Science Board; Regulatory biology panel, Research for Prevention of Blindness, Scientific advisory panel, Rutgers University, Institute of microbiology, Scientific advisory committee Scientists' Institute for Public Information: Chairman of the board and President of the executive committee Sloan-Kettering Institute for Cancer Research, Board of scientific consultants
Editorial responsibilities comprise Annual reviews, Assistant managing editor, Biochimica et biophysica acta, editorial board, Genetics, editorial board, Journal of biological chemistry, editorial board, Science, editorial board, Scientific monthly, editorial board, Frontiers of Biology, co-editor with A. Neuberger, Perspectives in biology and medicine, advisory board
Family Note 1934 married June Alton (divorced November 1956), Children: Miss Barbara Tatum, Mill Valley, California; Mrs. Margaret Easter, Palo Alto, California, Three grandchildren, 1956 married Viola Kantrowitz (died April 1974), 1975 married Elsie Bergland, Sister: Mrs. Bessie Rasmussen, Santa Monica, California, Brother: Dr. Howard J. Tatum, Associate medical director, Population Council
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The papers of Edward Lawrie Tatum were deposited with the Rockefeller University Archives on July 31, 1976 by Barbara Tatum and Margaret Easter.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 T189
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: biographical material, correspondence, subject files, meeting minutes, reports, manuscript material, laboratory notes, slides, negatives, film, photographs, and reprints.
Genetics; Yeast; Molds (Fungi); Bacteria; Physiology; Medical research; Medical sciences; Medicine, Preventive; Biology -- Research; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Biochemistry; Rockefeller University; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Biographical material, 1; 3 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Consists of biographical sketches; bibliography; personal correspondence; obituary material; committee memberships; theses; photographs; news clippings; fan mail; memorabilia; awards; honorary degrees; Nobel prize and related items and political and social involvements.
  - Biographical sketches, 1954-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Consists mainly of biographical sketches to fulfill requests of various organizations and publications. Also includes 1954 biographical sketch of Arthur L. Tatum (E.L. Tatum's father); 1977 and 1979 biographical sketches by Joshua Lederberg; an undated poem "A genetic code-or-a melan coli tale" by D.E. Nicholson.
  - Bibliography, 1932-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Prepared for Table of Contents in bound volumes in RU Archives.
  - Personal correspondence, 1957-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Consists of correspondence and membership certificates on election to various societies; statements on career development; offers of positions particularly an exchange with Kingman Brewster of Yale; housing problems; history of RU service (listing of position, laboratory, salaries).
    Special correspondents: Walter Bauer, Waldo R. Flinn (handwritten), Stanford Moore, C.B. Van Niel (handwritten), George Palade (?) (handwritten), yton Rous (handwritten), Victor Twitty, Maurice Wilkins (handwritten).
  - Correspondence with daughters, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Correspondence with and about daughters Margaret and Barbara.
  - Correspondence - George W. Beadle, 1949 undated 1964 1966 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Miscellaneous correspondence from and concerning George Beadle.
  - Obituary material, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Correspondence includes RU announcement; New York Times obituary; News and Notes 1975 November and December articles; announcement of 1975 Dec 11 RU memorial service and photocopies of contributions to E.L. Tatum postdoctoral fellowship fund.
  - RU memorial service tape, 1975 December 11 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Includes speakers: George W. Beadle, J.P. Cobb, D.R. Goddard, R. Meader, E. Reich, C.A. Williams.
  - Committee memberships (Box 1, Folder 8)
    A listing prepared in Dr. Tatum's office but not quite accurate.
  - Theses, 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Copies of theses for A.B. 1931; M.S. 1932; Ph. D 1934 granted at the University of Wisconsin.
  - Photographs, circa 1958-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Includes some scientific photographs. Identified where possible.
    Assorted photographs of E.L. Tatum; some of others.
  - Album of newsclipping, 1959-1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Newspaper articles concerning E.L. Tatum.
  - Fan mail, 1965-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Primarily requests for photographs of E.L. Tatum; some requests for scientific information and copies of addresses.
  - Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 13)
    American Airlines certificate; birthday and other card.
  - Amateur Chamber Music Players (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Includes printed material about Amateur Chamber Players.
    Correspondence indicates E.L. Tatum attempts to establish woodwind ensemble and willingness of some RI staff to join.
  - Awards; honorary degrees; and Nobel prize and related items
    Arrangement note
    Arranged in approximate chronological order.
    - Awards and honorary degrees
      - E.L. Tatum receives University of Wisconsin Man of the Year award, 1959 February 24-1964 June (Box 2, Folder 1)
        Correspondence includes material on selection of 1960 Man of the Year award. Also includes material on E.L. Tatum receives honorary Doctor of Science degree from University of Wisconsin.
      - E.L. Tatum receives City of Hope 2nd Salute to Medical research award, 1959 November 29 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        Other recipients: Selman Waksman, George W. Beadle, Steven O. Schwartz and Mrs. Mary Lasker. Correspondence includes program and newspaper article.
      - Rutgers University 10th Anniversary of Institute of Microbiology. E.L. Tatum receives honorary Doctor of Science degree and delivers paper "Microbes: Catalysts of concepts in biology", 1964 June 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
        Correspondence includes program and handwritten outline of presentation with working materials.
      - Centennial of science at Notre Dame E.L. Tatum receives honorary of Doctor of Laws degree, 1965 May 25 (Box 2, Folder 4)
        Correspondence.
      - Trinity College Convocation "Reflections on the future - The life sciences" for groundbreaking of Life Sciences Center, E.L. Tatum receives honorary Doctor of Science degree and delivers paper "Reflections on the future - frontiers in molecular genetics", 1965 October 30 (Box 2, Folder 5)
        Correspondence includes program and various copies of: abstract, presentation and outlines.
      - Yeshiva University, special convocation at Albert Einstein College of Medicine E.L. Tatum receives honorary Doctor of science degree. Correspondence, 1968 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Northwestern University E.L. Tatum receives honorary Doctor of Science degree, 1971 June 13 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        Correspondence includes RU News and Notes corrected brief about honorary degree.
    - Nobel prize and related items (Box 2)
      - E.L. Tatum receives Nobel prize in medicine and physiology jointly with George W. Beadle and other half to Joshua Lederberg, 1958 December 10 1941-1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        Correspondence includes announcements of prize; letters of congratulations from famous people; newspaper articles; invitations to speak at other institutions (delivers paper at Carlsberg Laboratorium). Also includes copies of E.L. Tatum Nobel lecture in various draft forms and printer's proof "A case history in biological research". Published in: Les prix Nobel in 1958, Stockholm, 1959. pp. 160-169 and in Science 123 (1959) 1711-1715 and copies of Tatum presentation at Nobel banquet and reprint of Beadle and Tatum "Genetic control of biochemical reactions in Neurospora". Published in PNAS 27 (1941) 499-506. [Reprint lacking in bound volume]. Also includes reprint of George W. Beadle Nobel lecture "Genes and chemical reactions in Neurospora".
      - Collection of published papers. Selected by Dr. Tatum having relevance to Nobel prize work (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Gustavus Adolphus Nobel conferences, 1965-1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        Dr. Tatum a member of Gustavus Adolphus Nobel conferences advisory committee. Correspondence deals with planning of various conferences. [For those meetings attended see under: Meetings: 1965 Jan 7-8 First Nobel conference in box no. 38 and 1971 Jan 6-7 Nobel conference in box no. 40].
      - Nobel prize - Miscellaneous, 1961-1973 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
        Correspondence includes:.
        Support of various nominations for Nobel prize.
        Endorses and issues statements on effect of Nobel prize.
        Requests for photographs of Dr. Tatum.
      - Lindau, Sweden, 22nd meeting of Nobel prize winners. Dr. Tatum attends and on June 28 delivers paper "Biochemical genetics of morphogenesis in Neurospora", 1972 June 26-30 (Box 2, Folder 12)
        Correspondence includes preliminary program and copies of presentation.
        E.L. Tatum does not attend; but is listed as member of Nobel conferences advisory committee with photograph.
      - Bound volume of Gustavus Adolphus Nobel conference "The Uniqueness of Man" - official transcript, 1968 (Package 2a)
  - Political and social involvements, 3 folders (Box 3)
    File consists of statements and correspondence on various political and social issues made as a famous individual scientist or Nobel Laureate.
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - 1963-1967 July (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1967 October-1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1946 1948-1975; 2
  Indications are that many of E.L. Tatum's replies are handwritten and not available. Many incoming letters are not dated. Included in many folders are recommendations for students and colleagues and many manuscripts for joint papers.
  Number in parenthesis indicates number of items. Includes handwritten letters by E.L. Tatum.
  Arranged in alphabetical order.
  - A-Au
    - Adelberg, E.A., 1951-1960; 8 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Adler, K., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Ahmad, M., 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Airth, B., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Altman, M., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - American Committee for the Weizmann Institute of Science, 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - American Freedom from Hunger Foundation, 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - American Naturalist, 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Analytical Biochemistry, 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Appleton-Century-Crofts, 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Aposhian, H.V., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Archives of Biochemistry and Biophysics, 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Arikian, N., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Arnold, A., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Ashman, J. Reply to question "Is God dead? ", 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Australian National University, 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - American Type Culture Collection As Nobel Laureate, E.L. Tatum Sponsor of ATCC Development Program, 6 letters (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - B-Bu
    - Baillaud, L., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Barker, J.W., 8 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Baron, R., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Barrales, H.L., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Basch, R.S. At RU, 1964-1966; 5 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Bearn, A.G., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Belizaire, M.S., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Beljanski, M., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Benedict, R.R., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Benn, N., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Besser, M., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Biochemical Society. In 1958 E.L. Tatum becomes member of, 1958-1965; 15 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Biochemistry, 10 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Blum, H.F., 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Co., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Bodenstein, D., 1959-1971; 13 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Bogdanovic, S.B. At RU 1968 Oct-1969 Mar as NSF senior foreign scientist fellow, 1961-1971; 19 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Brahznikova, M.G., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Brainerd, J.L., 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Brandt, W.H. At RU, 1969-1970; 23 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Braziller, George Inc., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Brearley School, 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - British Broadcasting Corp., 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Brown, Harris, Stevens, Inc., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Bryson, V., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Buzzati-Traverso, A.A., 4 letters (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Barratt, R.W. (ca 1 inch), 1952-1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Battley, E.H. Stanford student, 1955-1961; 64 letters (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Beam, C.A. Yale student, 1948-1963; 58 letters (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Bonner, David M., 1948-1964; 49 letters (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Brody, S. At RU, 1964-1967 1962-1972; 47 letters (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - C-Cu
    - Carson, S.F., 16 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Cary-Grove Community High School, 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Cassidy, H.G., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Catcheside, D.G., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Cerutti, P.A., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Chargaff, E., 6 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Chattofadhyay, P.K., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Chaudhuri, B.K., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Cheadle, V.I., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Clutterbuck, J. At RU, 1973 January-August; 14 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Cocioba, I.D., 6 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Cohen, S.S., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Colowick, S.P., 3 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Corcos, A., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Costello, D.P., 1 letter (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Cowdry, E.V., 1960 1968-1969; 20 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Curran, F., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Cutting, W.C., 2 letters (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Includes birthday congratulations upon retirement.
    - Cerami, Anthony. RU student and Professor, 1966-1975; 17 letters (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Colburn, R.W. (Stanford student), 1952-1968; 66 letters (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Commoner, Barry, 1964 1970; 11 letters (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Corzo, R.H. Stanford student, 26 letters (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Includes 2 handwritten items from C.B. van Niel.
    - Crocken, Barbara At RU, 1963-1967; 43 letters (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - D-Du
    - Danforth, C.H. Congratulations on C.H. Danforth 80th birthday, 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Danielli, J., 1 letter (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Daniels, F., 1 letter (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Daque, N., 1 letter (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Dascher, C., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - David-Stewart Publishing Co., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - DeBey, H.J., 1 letter (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - deKoven, D., 11 letters (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Demme, G.K., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - deSolis, E., 1 letter (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Diorio, J., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Dodge, B.O. Primarily about honorary degrees for, 7 letters (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Doelle, H.W. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Dubos, R. RU Professor, 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - DuShane, G., 1 letter (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - de Terra, Noel. At RI, 1958-1974 1959-1962; 86 letters (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Doy, Colin H., 26 letters (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Dutta, S.K., 1966 1968-1975; 72 letters (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - E-Ep
    - Ebersold, W.T., 5 letters (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Economous, C., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Edgarton, D. Mrs, 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Edizioni Scientifiche e Tecniche Mondadori, 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Elliott, C.G., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Engel, L., 2 letters (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Environment Environmental Fund, 21 letters (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Epstein, H.F., 1 letter (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Eberhart, Bruce M. Stanford student, 1955-1972; 63 letters (Box 5, Folder 9)
      Includes: Lecture: 1965 May 10 Greensboro, N.C. University of N.C. Freshman honors program. Panel discussion on the relationship between the humanities and science "on biochemical genetics".
    - Ehrensvard, G., 1953 1959-1966; 25 letters (Box 5, Folder 10)
      Includes 1 spiral notebook of Tatum handwritten notes of 1953 Summer Ehrensvard lectures.
    - Eversole, R.A. Stanford student, 1954-1968; 82 letters (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - F-Fr
    - Falkow, S., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Fincham, J.R.S., 4 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - First National City Bank, 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Flynn, J.E., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Food and Population, 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Fox, S.W., 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Friedman, H.M., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Fries, N., 4 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Fromageot, P. At RU, 1965 October-1966 June; 19 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Federation of American Scientists, 46 letters (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Includes Dr. Tatum's endorsements as member and sponsor of the federation.
    - Fels Research Institute E.L. Tatum becomes member of Scientific Advisory Board of, 1972 January; 23 letters (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Folkers, Karl, 1964-1974; 45 letters (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Fristrom, James. RU graduate student, 1962-1968; 35 letters (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Includes E.L. Tatum's presentation for degree granting.
    - Fuller, R.C. Stanford student, 1950-1965; 32 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - G-Gr
    - Gafford, R.D., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Gal, E.M., 8 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Galen, B., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Gangadharan, G., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Garfield, E., 3 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Gause, G.F., 5 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Gente, 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Ghora, B.K., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Giese, A., 5 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Giles, N., 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Goldberg, I.H., 6 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Includes NSF grant application evaluation with application.
    - Goldberg, L., 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Goldstein, P., 4 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Gopal-Ayengar, A.R., 1966 1969-1974; 31 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Includes items on N.K. Notani.
    - Grace, E.J., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Gray, G.W., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Griffin, A.C., 12 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Grigg, G., 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Garnjobst, Laura At RI, 1949 1956-1975 1957-1966; 113 letters (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Includes correspondence with others involving L. Garnjobst re: stocks of morphological mutants and some Garnjobst laboratory notes.
    - Georgi, C.E, 1957-1963; 25 letters (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Includes University of Nebraska, Missouri Valley Branch of the Society of American Bacteriologists meeting Delivers paper. 1959 Apr 17-18.
    - Gross, S.R. At Stanford 1953-1957; At RU, 1953-1969; 79 letters (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - H-I
    - Hameed, A., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Hamilton, W.F., 3 letters (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Hanna, M.G., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Harcourt, Brace & World, Inc., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Hassenstein, C., 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Hentsch & Cie, 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Hermann, H., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 11)